<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>FTP Connector (Labs)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Connects to remote file system via FTP in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node connects to a remote FTP server. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the <i>files</i> of the remote server, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for FTP are specified with a UNIX-like syntax such as /myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            path for FTP consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Host">
	            Address of the host where the FTP server runs.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Port">
	            Port that the FTP server is listening on for incoming connections.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Authentication">
	            Method of authentication to use.
	            <ul>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Credentials:</b> Authenticate with the username and password of the selected credentials flow variable.
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Username/password:</b> Authenticate with the provided <b>Username</b> and <b>Password</b>. The password is persistently stored
	            		(in encrypted form) in the settings of this node. The password may be empty if the SSH server permits empty passwords. 
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Anonymous:</b> Authenticate with the <b>anonymous</b> user name and blank password.
	            	</li>
	           	</ul>
	        </option>
		    <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is the root "/".
		    </option>
	    </tab>

        <tab name="Advanced">
		    <option name="Connection timeout">
		        Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Time zone offset from GMT">
		        Server time zone offset from Greenwich Mean Time (minutes). 
		    </option>
		    
		    <option name="Minimum pool size">
		        Minimal number of connected and logged in FTP clients in resource pool
		        the node will try to open. Actual number of connections may be less,
		        depending on the limits of the FTP server. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Core pool size">
		        Core FTP clients pool size.
		    </option>
		    <option name="Maximum pool size">
		        Maximum possible FTP clients in pool size. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Maximum idle time">
		        The number of seconds which FTP client can be inactive before close if the number of clients in pool
		        is more then minimum pool size. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Use SSL">
		        If this options selected, then FTPS protocol with explicit mode and TLS will used for connection.
		    </option>
		    <option name="Use Proxy">
		        If this options selected, then configured HTTP Proxy from global Eclipse preferences will used for connection.
		        This option is incompatible with 'Use SSL'.
		    </option>
		</tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
   		<outPort index="0" name="FTP File System Connection">
   			FTP File System Connection.
   		</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
