<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>FTP Connector</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Connects to remote file system via FTP in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node connects to a remote FTP server. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the <i>files</i> of the remote server, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for FTP are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, for example
            <tt>/myfolder/file.csv</tt>, which is an absolute path that consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash (<tt>/</tt>).</li>
                    <li>The name of a folder (<tt>myfolder</tt>), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a file (<tt>file.csv</tt>).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Host">
	            Address of the host where the FTP server runs.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Port">
	            Port that the FTP server is listening on for incoming connections.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Use FTPS">
	            Attempts to communicate with the server using TLS-encryption (FTPS in explicit mode). If this option is selected, then
	            it is not possible to connect using an HTTP proxy (see below).
	        </option>
	        <option name="Authentication">
	            Method of authentication to use.
	            <ul>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Username &amp; password:</b> Authenticate with a username and password. Either enter a <i>username</i> and
	            		<i>password</i>, in which case the password will be persistently stored (in encrypted form) with
	            		the workflow. Or check <i>Use credentials</i> and a select a credentials flow variable to supply
	            		the username and password.
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Anonymous:</b> Authenticate with the <i>anonymous</i> user and a blank password.
	            	</li>
	           	</ul>
	        </option>
		    <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is the root "/".
		    </option>
	    </tab>

        <tab name="Advanced">
		    <option name="Connection timeout">
		        Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Read timeout">
		        Timeout in seconds to read a server response from a connection, or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Minimum FTP connections">
		        Minimum number of (control) connections to open to the FTP server.
		    </option>
		    <option name="Maximum FTP connections">
		        Maximum number of (control) connections to open to the FTP server.
		    </option>
		    <option name="Use HTTP Proxy">
		        If this option is selected, then the currently configured HTTP proxy from the KNIME preferences 
		        will used to connect. This option is incompatible with 'Use FTPS'.
		    </option>
		    <option name="Time zone offset from GMT">
		        Server time zone offset from Greenwich Mean Time (minutes). 
		    </option>
		</tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
   		<outPort index="0" name="FTP File System Connection">
   			FTP File System Connection.
   		</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
