<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>SMB Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to an SMB server (e.g. Samba, or Windows Server) in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node connects to a remote SMB server (e.g. Samba, or Windows Server). The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            <i>files</i>, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...). This node generally
            supports versions 2 and 3 of the SMB protocol. It also supports connecting to a
            <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/storage/dfs-namespaces/dfs-overview">Windows DFS namespace</a>.
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for SMB are specified similar to Windows Paths, but with a leading backslash (<tt>\</tt>).
            The path is interpreted relative to the chosen <i>Share</i>  (or DFS namespace). For example
            <tt>\myfolder\file.csv</tt>, is an absolute path that consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading backslash (<tt>\</tt>).</li>
                    <li>The name of a folder (<tt>myfolder</tt>), followed by a backslash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a file (<tt>file.csv</tt>).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="Connect to">
                Specifies whether to connect by specifying a <b>file server</b> host or a <b>Windows domain</b>.
                
                <p>
                Choosing <b>File server</b> specifies that a direct connection shall be made
                to access a file share on a specific file server. A file server is any machine that runs an SMB service, such as those provided by
                <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/storage/file-server/file-server-smb-overview">Windows Server</a>
                and <a href="https://www.samba.org/">Samba</a>. For example, this mode is similar to connecting to <tt>\\server.company.com\marketing</tt> 
                using the Windows Explorer, which makes a direct connection to the SMB service running on <tt>server.company.com</tt>.
                </p>
                
                <p>
                Choosing <b>Domain</b> specifies that a connection shall be made to access a file share in a Windows Active Directory domain.
                For example, this mode is similar to connecting to <tt>\\company.com\marketing</tt> 
                using the Windows Explorer, which first locates and then connects to an SMB service that provides the <tt>marketing</tt> file share (or
                <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/storage/dfs-namespaces/dfs-overview">DFS namespace</a>)
                 for the Windows domain <tt>company.com</tt>.
                </p>
            </option>

        	<option name="Host">
	            <i>When using "File server" connection:</i>Hostname of the host where the SMB server runs, e.g. <tt>server.company.com</tt>.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Port">
	            <i>When using "File server" connection:</i>Port that the SMB server is listening on for incoming connections.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Share">
	        	<i>When using "File server" connection:</i>The name of the file share provided by the SMB server. The name of the file share must not
	        	contain any backslashes.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Domain">
	        	<i>When using "Domain" connection:</i>The name of the Windows domain (Active Directory), e.g. <tt>company.com</tt>.
	        </option>
            <option name="Share/Namespace">
                <i>When using "Domain" connection:</i>The name of the file share (or
                <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/storage/dfs-namespaces/dfs-overview">DFS namespace</a>) to access. The name
                of the file share/namespace must not contain any backslashes.
            </option>

	        <option name="Authentication">
	            Method of authentication to use:
	            <ul>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Username &amp; password:</b> Authenticate with a username and password (the underlying authentication mechanism is NTLM).
	            		Either enter a <i>username</i> and <i>password</i> here, in which case the password will be persistently stored (in encrypted form) with
                        the workflow. Or check <i>Use credentials</i> and a select a credentials flow variable to supply
                        the username and password. Note that the username field also accepts usernames of the form <tt>DOMAIN\user</tt>
                        and <tt>user@DOMAIN</tt>. 
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Kerberos:</b> Authenticate using an existing Kerberos ticket.
	            	</li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Guest:</b> Authenticate as the <tt>Guest</tt> user (without password).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>Anonymous:</b> Authenticate with an empty username (without password).
                    </li>
	           	</ul>
	        </option>
	        <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading backslash. The default working directory is "\".
		    </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
        	<option name="Read/Write timeout">
        		The timeout for read/write operations (in seconds).
        	</option>
        	<option name="SMB version(s)">
        		The option allows to enforce the usage of specific SMB protocol version(s).
        		Selecting <b>Auto</b> option will make the node to choose the highest version supported by
        		both this node and the SMB server.
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="SMB File System Connection">
             SMB File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
