<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./zip.png" type="Sink">
	<name>Zip Files</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Zips files into a zip file.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>This node zips files into a zip file. The path to the files has
			to be contained in the input table.
		</intro>


		<option name="Location column">
			The column that contains the location to the files
			that
			should be zipped.
			The location has to contain the absolute path.
			It can either be a
			String or an URI.
		</option>
		<option name="Output file">
			Path of the zip file that will be created.
		</option>
		<option name="Compression level">
			Level of compression for the zip file.
		</option>
		<option name="Path handling">
			Specifies how the file path shall be handled inside the zip file.
			<br />
			<b>Use full path</b>
			<br />
			The full filepath will be used for every file.
			<br />
			<b>Use only filename</b>
			<br />
			Only the filename will be used, so the zip file will contain no
			directories.
			<br />
			<b>Truncate prefix</b>
			<br />
			The given prefix will be cut off the files path inside the zip file.
			To locate the files, the full path is still required in the input
			table.
		</option>
		<option name="Prefix directory">
			Prefix of the path that will be truncated.
		</option>
		<option name="If zip file exists...">
			Specifies the behavior if a zip file with the same name already
			exists.
			<br />
			<b>Overwrite</b>
			<br />
			Overwrites the whole file and ignores its content.
			<br />
			<b>Append (Overwrite)</b>
			<br />
			Appends the new files into the existing zip file. It will overwrite
			files within the zip file that have the same name as new ones.
			<br />
			<b>Append (Abort)</b>
			<br />
			Appends the new files into the existing zip file. It will abort if
			the zip files contains files that would need to be overwritten. In
			this case the old file will be retained as it is.
			<br />
			<b>Abort</b>
			<br />
			Will abort if the zip file already exists, while keeping the file
			untouched.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">Has to have a column that contains the
			path to the files that should be zipped.
		</inPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
