<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png" type="Source"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>ZIP Archive Connector</name>

	
    <shortDescription>
        This node creates a file system connection that allows to read the files/folders stored inside
        a ZIP archive.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node creates a file system connection that allows to read the files/folders stored inside
        		a ZIP archive. The resulting file system connection output port allows downstream nodes to
        		read the compressed files from a zip archive file.
            </p>

            <p>
                <b>Path syntax:</b>
                Paths for this connector are specified with a UNIX-like syntax such
                as /myfolder/myfile. An absolute
                path consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the
                        above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Note:</b> When the ZIP file changes, this node has to be reset and re-executed,
                otherwise its behavior is undefined, which may result in errors and/or invalid data
                being read. 
            </p>

        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="Read from">
                Select a file system which stores the data you want to read. There are
                four default file system options to choose from:
                <br />
                <ul>
                    <li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a file/folder from your
                        local system.
                    </li>
                    <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to read from a mountpoint.
                        When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
                        Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
                        Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
                        A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
                        You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
                    </li>
                    <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
                        relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
                    When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
                    </li>
                    <li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
                        When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and read timeout in milliseconds.
                        In case it takes longer to connect to the host / read the file, the node fails to execute.
                        Browsing is disabled for this option.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                To read from other file systems, click on
                <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
                <i>Add File System Connection port</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector
                node to the newly added input port. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
                It is greyed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
                Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
            </option>
            <option name="Working directory">
                Specify the
                <i>working directory</i>
                of the resulting file system connection, using the
                <b>Path syntax</b>
                explained above. The working
                directory must be specified as an
                absolute path. A working directory allows
                downstream nodes to access
                files/folders using
                <i>relative</i>
                paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading backslash. The default
                working directory is "\".
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Encoding">
        	<option name="Use default encoding">
        		If selected, uses a default encoding (currently UTF-8) to read the names of the compressed files in the archive.
        		If you notice that the names of the files in zip archive contain '?' characters, then UTF-8 might be
        		wrong. In this case, uncheck the box and pick the correct encoding, e.g. try
        		<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_page_437">CP437</a> which is used in some ZIP files.
        	</option>
            <option name="Encoding">
                Sets the character set/encoding to use when reading the names of the compressed files in the archive. By default,
                <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_page_437">CP437</a> is chosen, which is used in some ZIP files. You can specify
                any other encoding supported by Java. Choosing "OS default" uses the default encoding of the Java VM, which may depend on
                the locale or the Java property &quot;file.encoding&quot;.
            </option>
        </tab>  
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
       <dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Input File System" group-identifier="Input File System"> 
            File system that can be used to provide a zip archive file. 
        </dynInPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="ZIP Archive File System Connection">
            ZIP Archive File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
