<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./upload16x16.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Upload (legacy)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Uploads files and folders to a server.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        		<i>This is a legacy file handling node and will be replaced in the foreseeable future.
        		For further information about the new file handling framework see the </i>
        		<a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.
        		</i></a><br/>
			</p>
            This node uploads the files and folders referenced by the
            table to
            the server specified by the connection information.
        </intro>


        <option name="Target folder">
            Location on the server where the files will be put.
        </option>
        <option name="Source">
            Column of the input table with the URIs to
            the files.
        </option>
        <option name="Path handling">
            How the path of the source files will be truncated.
            <br />
            <b>Use full path</b>
            <br />
            Use the full path without truncating anything.
            <br />
            <b>Use only filename</b>
            <br />
            Truncate the whole path and leave only the name of the file.
            <br />
            <b>Truncate prefix</b>
            <br />
            Truncate the selected prefix directory from the path.
        </option>
        <option name="Prefix">
            Directory that will be truncated from the
            sources path.
        </option>
        <option name="If exists...">
            How to handle already existing files.
            <br />
            <b>Overwrite</b>
            <br />
            Overwrite the existing file.
            <br />
            <b>Overwrite if newer</b>
            <br />
            Overwrite the existing file only, if the local file is
            newer.
            <br />
            <b>Abort</b>
            <br />
            Abort the execution of the node.
        </option>
        <option name="Abort if transfer fails">
            If this is checked the node will abort if 
            one of the files could not be transferred. 
            If it is unchecked the output table will contain 
            a column that indicates whether or not 
            the file could be successfully transferred.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Connection information port" index="0">
            Port
            object
            containing the connection information to the server.
        </inPort>
        <inPort name="Filelist port" index="1">
            Table containing the
            list of files that should be uploaded.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Filelist table" index="0">
            Table containing
            the
            list of files that have been uploaded and if they have
            been uploaded or were already up to date. If files are
            allowed to fail there is an additional column, that will indicate
            if the transfer was successful or did fail.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
