<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./zip16x16.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Zip Files (legacy)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Zips files into an archive.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node zips files into an archive. The path to the
			files has
			to be contained in the input table.
            <p>
                <i>This is a legacy file handling node and will be replaced in the foreseeable future.
                For further information about the new file handling framework see the </i>
                <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.
                </i></a><br/>
            </p>
		</intro>


		<option name="Location column">
			The column that contains the location to the files
			that
			should be archived.
			The location has to contain the absolute path.
			It can either be a
			String or an URI.
		</option>
		<option name="Output format">
			Specifies the format of the output file.
			<br />
			<b>zip</b>
			<br />
			A zip file.
			<br />
			<b>tar.gz</b>
			<br />
			Tar file compressed with gzip.
			<br />
			<b>tar.bz2</b>
			<br />
			Tar file compressed with bzip2.
		</option>
		<option name="Output file">
			Path of the archive that will be created. You can use local filesystem paths or URL, given that they are
			allow for writing.
		</option>
		<option name="Path handling">
			Specifies how the file path shall be handled inside the archive.
			<br />
			<b>Use full path</b>
			<br />
			The full filepath will be used for every file.
			<br />
			<b>Use only filename</b>
			<br />
			Only the filename will be used, so the archive will contain no
			directories.
			<br />
			<b>Truncate prefix</b>
			<br />
			The given prefix will be cut off of the file paths inside the
			archive.
			To locate the files, the full path is still required in the
			input
			table.
		</option>
		<option name="Prefix directory">
			Prefix of the path that will be truncated.
		</option>
		<option name="If file exists...">
			Specifies the behavior if a file with the same name
			already
			exists.
			<br />
			<b>Overwrite</b>
			<br />
			Overwrites the whole file and ignores its content.
			<br />
			<b>Append (Overwrite)</b>
			<br />
			Appends the new files into the existing archive. It will
			overwrite
			files within the archive that have the same name as new ones.
			<br />
			<b>Append (Abort)</b>
			<br />
			Appends the new files into the existing archive. It will
			abort if
			the
			archive contains files that would need to be overwritten. In
			this case
			the old file will be retained as it is.
			<br />
			<b>Abort</b>
			<br />
			Will abort if the file already exists, while keeping the
			file
			untouched.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">Has to have a column that contains
			the
			path to the files that should be archived.
		</inPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
