<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./sshconnection16x16.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>SSH Connector (Labs)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to remote file system via SSH in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node connects to a remote SSH server using SFTP. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the <i>files</i> of the remote server, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for SSH are specified with a UNIX-like syntax such as /myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            path for SSH consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Host">
	            Address of the host where the SSH server runs.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Port">
	            Port that the SSH server is listening on for incoming connections.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Authentication">
	            Specify the authentication method to use:
	            <ul>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Credentials:</b> Authenticate with the username and password of the selected credentials flow variable.
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Username/password:</b> Authenticate with the provided <i>Username</i> and <i>Password</i>. The password is persistently stored
	            		(in encrypted form) in the settings of this node and will be saved with the workflow. The password may be empty if the SSH server
	            		permits empty passwords. 
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Key file:</b> Authenticate using a private key file. You have to specify the <i>Username</i> and the private <i>Key file</i>. 
	            		A <i>Key passphrase</i> can optionally be provided, in case the private 
	            		key file is passphrase-protected. Note that the passphrase is persistently stored (in encrypted form) in the settings
	            		of this node and will be saved with the workflow. This node supports the following private key formats:
	            		 <i>RFC4716</i> (default OpenSSH2 private key format), <i>PKCS#8</i>, <i>PKCS#1</i> (traditional PEM format, OpenSSL-compatible),
	            		 and <i>ppk</i> (PuTTY format).
	            	</li>
	           	</ul>
	        </option>
		    <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is the root "/".
		    </option>
	    </tab>
	    
        <tab name="Advanced">
		    <option name="Connection timeout">
		        Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Maximum SFTP sessions">
		        Number of SFTP sessions the node will try to open. Actual number of sessions may be less,
		        depending on the limits of the SSH server. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Use known hosts file">
		        If this options selected, then provided known hosts file will be used to validate the (public) key of the SSH server. If not
		        selected, then server key will not be validated.
		    </option>
		</tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Input File System" group-identifier="Input File System"> 
			File system that can be used to provide an SSH private key and/or known hosts file. 
		</dynInPort>
   		<outPort index="0" name="SSH File System Connection">
   			SSH File System Connection.
   		</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
